Hi everyone. Let's get started. In the
past couple lectures, we've been talking
about training RL and imitation learning
systems that can do multiple different
tasks. Uh and we first looked at this
from the lens of multitask imitation and
reinforcement learning where you
condition a policy or a Q function uh
not just on the state but also on some
sort of descriptor of the task or where
there are also scenarios in the goal
condition setting where that descriptor
could actually be a state itself uh like
a goal state that you're trying to
reach. And then more recently we were
talking about meta reinforcement
learning where you could think of that
instead of uh kind of conditioning on a
description of the task you want to do.
You actually need to figure out from a
few examples uh and a little bit of
experience with rewards what the task
is. Uh and you're trying to train this
sort of like fshot policy that can adapt
with a small amount of experience.
Now today um we'll be kind of building
on some of these concepts and trying to
not just train a policy to do multiple
tasks but to actually string together
behaviors for multiple tasks into a
longer horizon task.
So, um, this is where, uh, we're going
to be talking about where hierarchy
might be helpful for solving long
horizon tasks. And then we'll be talking
about some of the key design choices
behind hierarchical imitation and
reinforcement learning methods,
including how to represent skills and
goals, when to move on from one goal or
task to another, and the supervision for
the different levels of the hierarchy.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh and then lastly, we'll go through a
couple examples of like what these
systems could actually look like. Uh
because there are like a variety of
different ways that you could design
these sort of hierarchical systems. So
the tasks that we'll be talking about
today are long horizon tasks. Uh and by
long horizon tasks I mean tasks that
take a while to complete and might
consist of a number of different
subtasks or a number of different steps
that you need to take in some sort of
sequence or order in order to complete
it successfully. So this could be
something like cooking a meal. Uh it
could be for like a robot system. Uh for
a like an LLM agent, it could be trying
to fix a bug that's causing um a neural
network training loss to explode. Uh for
an autonomous vehicle, it could be
driving to Yusede. Uh for a um a
different sort of LLM, it could be
giving feedback on a long report. Uh and
for these tasks, you can think about how
there are often times different steps
that you need to complete. Uh some of
those steps might be
um interdependent on one another where
it makes sense to do one before the
other. Uh and other tasks might be
something where they're less
interdependent and it's actually okay to
do those in parallel.
uh these are really hard problems for AI
systems to solve in general. Uh and the
reason for that is um there's kind of a
number of reasons for that. So uh the
first is that when you are doing a task
that takes a long time, you're visiting
a large number of states uh along the
way to get there. And every new state
that you visit, you need to be able to
make decisions for. Uh so you had
basically just have a much broader
distribution that your policy needs to
be successful on. Uh there's also a lot
of different opportunities to make
mistakes. Uh and if you make a mistake,
you need to be able to recover from that
mistake. Uh if it's something that you
can actually recover from. Uh and
separate from mistakes, there's also
just opportunities to get stuck. Uh for
example, if there's kind of one kind of
mistake that might, for example, not
lead you to actually make progress on
the task. And
if you're not making progress, then
you'll actually just end up in the same
state again.
And you'll keep on making that same
mistake over and over again and
essentially just get stuck at performing
the task. Uh, and these kinds of
mistakes are kind of particularly gnarly
because they um when you end up in the
same state again, your policy will keep
on kind of deterministically staying in
that state and never making forward
progress towards the goal. Um, and then
what's the main idea behind hierarchy?
So uh we've talked about multitask
policies where uh you have some actually
let me draw this further to the right.
Uh we have some policy that uh takes as
input um some state maybe the state at
some time step and it also takes as
input some task or some goal. Uh I'm
going to write this as G for now because
this this task or goal could take a
number of different forms. And this is
passed into your policy to produce
actions that are trying to address that
particular goal.
The idea for trying to solve long
horizon tasks is if we have a policy
that can do a number of different
things, uh then we could try to break up
a bigger task into um into different
subtasks and then use um use one policy
to actually tell this policy what task
it should be doing at any given point in
time.
So for example, you could uh
have another policy here that's actually
outputting the goals to be doing. Uh and
this policy should also have information
about the state as input. Uh so that it
knows where it is and what goal makes
sense for the next uh for the agent to
do. Um, and then optionally this uh kind
of this is often called like a low-level
policy uh or we'll use pi ll to refer to
this is kind of the low-level policy.
This is doing shorter tasks and we could
refer to this as a highle policy uh
that's outputting goals for the
low-level policy to accomplish. Uh and
this policy it could have a task you may
also sorry I wrote this as lowle that
should be high level. Um
the if you want our your policy to be
able to do multiple long horizon tasks
then this highle policy could also have
some sort of task descriptor as input as
well or some sort of goal as input. Um
and so we for example could have goal
high level as input to this policy. uh
if you want to be completing not just
one long horizon task but multiple long
horizon tasks like not just driving to
Yusede but also being able to drive to
uh the Grand Canyon or LA or um Seattle
or something like that. And the kind of
crux underlying this idea is that if we
can break up a really long task into
smaller parts then we might be able to
better address the problem. And um say
for example your long horizon task is to
bake a cheesecake. Uh this is a really
really hard problem. And if you just
tried to train a policy um like like a
robot policy to output motor commands
for doing this task. Uh it's really hard
to figure out like what you should be
doing at any given point in time. Um but
if you're just starting out, you can
think about okay what's the first step
for accomplishing this? Maybe you need
to buy ingredients. Okay then what's the
first step of buying ingredients? Well
maybe you need to go to the store. And
how do you get to the store? Well, maybe
you need to walk to the door. To walk to
the door, you might take a step. Um, how
do you take a step? You might contract a
muscle. Uh, and so you can basically
break down um a bigger task into a much
smaller task. And these smaller tasks
are a lot easier to train uh systems to
do. And if you can train systems to do
the smaller tasks, then you can try to
compose them with like a higher level
policy to be able to accomplish that
more challenging task.
So um what we can do is for the bake a
cheesecake task we could pass this with
a state or observation into a highle
policy which is going to predict an
intermediate step like for example go to
the store or go to the door and then
that intermediate step along with the
stator observation will be passed to the
low-level policy to predict an action.
Um now a couple notes here. So um one
note is that the this low-level policy
uh this needs to be acting at the
original
kind of frequency. So if you're um if
you're controlling a robot maybe this is
operating at like 20 hertz. If you're
controlling a language model then this
is going to be outputting like word by
word. Uh whereas the high level policy
it could actually predict goals for the
lowle policy at a coarser time scale. Uh
and so for example, it could be
outputting goals after you've completed
a paragraph for a language model or
after you've completed that um like like
going to the store for example. It could
then give a new goal uh for the
low-level policy to perform. Um and so
we have a high level policy that
predicts intermediate goals and then the
low-le policy tries to accomplish those
intermediate goals by predicting
actions. Um typically the low-level
policy is operating at a higher
frequency than the highle policy.
And um I should note that I'm I'll refer
to these as kind of goals or subtasks.
Um there's a number of other names for
these as well like skills or options. Um
you could also think about these as
highle actions. So these are these are
actions but for a different policy
that's operating at a higher level of
abstraction than the original policy.
And then the other thing here is that um
this is kind of like a two-level
hierarchy. Uh but you could also imagine
having more than two levels of hierarchy
as well. And for example, the baking a
cheesecake, you could have um maybe one
level of hierarchy could be uh like
things like go to the store, like buy
the things, bring them back. Um and a
different level of hierarchy might
actually be controlling like the motors
on a robot in order to accomplish those
tasks.
Um and then once we have this sort of
hierarchal policy, how do we actually
like roll it out? If we can do these
things. So specifically if we're at like
say we'll start at t equals 1, then the
first step is to predict um or another
kind of way to think about kind of
predicting a goal is planning. Like
we're trying to think forward what is
the next step that we should do. So we
could try to plan a goal and this will
be by sampling from our highle policy
based off of the uh the current state
and optionally some sort of highle goal
and then we'll be repeatedly sampling
from our low-level policy. And so we
could repeat uh first sample
an action from the low-level policy
using this goal as input. So sample A
from high low level
with the state and this goal the goal
from the high level as input and then
we'll actually execute that action and
get the next state.
Uh
so basically at that point we'll then
kind of t will now become t + 1 and
we'll observe st then again with the
same goal as before but the new state
will then be sampling a new action
repeating this process
and then at some point after we have and
we'll talk a little bit about how we
decide when to get a new goal but when
we have decided that we're either done
with the goal or enough time has passed
then we'll will move back to step one to
replan uh a new goal based off of the
latest state.
Yeah. So the question is um so I let's
let's walk through this and then I'll
get to your question in a minute. So um
is there some initial state or
observation plan a new goal until a new
goal is selected. We're going to execute
um a predicted action according to our
low-level policy based off of that
predicted goal and then we'll observe a
new observation.
Now um why might hierarchy help? uh
which I think was kind of getting at
your question. There's a couple reasons
for this. So uh the first is that
typically
we're going to be training this
low-level policy to reach goals and this
highle policy to maximize rewards or
reach some high level goals. And this
means that the objective for this policy
is different than the overall objective
of completing the long horizon task. And
so this is actually getting different
supervision and this intermediate
supervision signal for how to complete
intermediate goals or tasks could be
useful for guiding the policy towards
completing the long horizon task. So you
can think about it potentially it kind
of depends on the setup but you can
think about it as a way to leverage
intermediate supervision.
Now you could always have intermediate
supervision when training a big flat
policy as well where you give it shaped
rewards and you give it rewards for
completing individual subtasks. But
compared to that, the other difference
here is that this low-level multitask
policy is going to be um able to more
explicitly share knowledge across the
different subtasks. Uh so the um because
for example it has this goal as input um
it's it's kind of targeting a particular
subtask and if two subtasks are quite
similar to one another then this the
kind of the um this policy will be able
to kind of share data across those tasks
in order to more efficiently learn
compared to if you were just to try to
train a single policy across the long
horizon task. In reinforcement learning
specifically, you can also think about
benefits in terms of exploration. Uh and
in particular when you are when this
high level policy is proposing kind of
goals to reach that's structuring the
exploration process to encourage it to
explore not just in the original action
space but also in this higher level goal
space.
Um and lastly uh there can also be
sometimes practical benefits as well.
So, for example, if you're thinking
about this task of uh making a
cheesecake, for example, you might need
to be reasoning through the steps for
how to do that. And if you have a single
policy, then you need to reason through
those steps every single time step uh
with with that flat policy. Uh so um if
your robot is operating at 20 hertz for
example, you're going to be reasoning
through like what is the next thing I
should be doing and the way to get there
with my action at every single time step
where here we can kind of run this
reasoning computation at a lower
frequency uh than the low-level policy.
So that that can be kind of a practical
benefit in terms of compute costs. Yeah.
So the question is um like can we
elaborate on the first point and how the
supervision for the low-level policy is
different for the high level policy. So
the high level policy is its goal is to
complete the long horizon task. Um so
its goal is to like bake the cheesecake
and it gets rewards when the cheesecake
is baked. Uh the low-level policy
um it gets rewards for completing
intermediate subtasks. Uh and so uh when
it for example uh finds the ingredients,
preheats the oven, that sort of thing,
it's getting rewards for completing
those tasks. um and that sort of
intermediate supervision guides it
towards completing the long horizon
task. Yeah. So the question is like what
if you need to be doing multiple tasks
at once. So in that case um unless your
low-level agent can like has like I
don't know 10 arms or something or can
output things in parallel you do need to
pick some order for that. Now um the
goal of the high level policy is to
figure out whether that order matters or
not. And so if it figures out that the
order um is really important, then it
will get rewards. It'll be better able
to predict those goals. If it predicts
the correct order, um in other
circumstances, if the order doesn't
matter, then um it will it should be
able to learn that and figure out that
um it doesn't really matter and it'll
just pick one arbitrarily.
Um, now there's also a question like of
whether or not we like actually need
multiple policies in order to get some
of these benefits. Uh, and we in the on
the last side we talked about kind of
the benefits of what you might get with
a hierarchal approach versus just a
what's called a flat policy with no
hierarchy, which is kind of the typical
pass in um the long horizon task and the
state and predict the action.
>> [snorts]
>> There's actually also an intermediate
approach that you can take as well that
actually retains a lot of the benefits
of hierarchy uh and actually in some
ways has a lot of the same design
choices. [snorts] Uh which is something
that's a little bit like chain of
thought in language models if you're
familiar with that. uh which is that if
you have some long horizon task, you
could have the policy first like reason
through what goal or what subtask it
should be completing and then predict
the low-level action. Uh so this is kind
of combining these uh these two policies
into one. Um but now you're just kind of
predicting them in sequence. You're
first predicting the goal and then the
action. Um this sort of approach can
actually retain a fair number of the
benefits. So it can benefit from the
same sort of intermediate supervision.
It also might have some practical
downsides. So this doesn't um have the
benefits of the kind of practical
computational benefits of separating
them into two because then you still
have to run this at the full frequency.
Um there isn't like entirely a
conclusion yet empirically on whether
this is um like just as good as a
hierarchal approach. Um, and you could
imagine that like there might be
benefits in terms of like sharing some
knowledge with low-level policies versus
with a combined approach. Um, so this is
like an open area of research on whether
or not you could just do this. Um, and
the only like really conclusive downside
would be um would be the kind of the
computational upside of having reasoning
at a lower frequency than taking actions
for the first one. So the question is
why is having intermediate supervision
helpful? Um, there's a couple reasons.
So, if you're in a reinforcement
learning setting and your goal is to
make a cheesecake and you only get
rewards when the cheesecake is baked um
versus not, then uh those rewards are
going to be really sparse and not
actually allow you to progress. Um the
second is that even if you say you were
in an imitation learning setting and you
um
and the like you're just predicting
actions like imitating actions for
making a cheesecake then uh sometimes
like if the policy isn't explicitly
thinking about what part of that task it
might be doing it might kind of
oscillate between different subtasks
especially if it doesn't have a history
of past uh past observations. Um so
there's like there's also even benefits
in imitation learning settings as well.
So now let's dive into some of the
design choices. Uh this will kind of
also start to answer some of the
questions that have come up as well. So
the first is that um we've kind of
abstractly been talking about these
different goals and uh we need to think
about how to actually represent those
different goals. Uh, and I'm actually
gonna let's I actually want to start
with this as an exercise uh for you all
to think about what um what different
representations might make sense for
different problems. And so I'll give you
a few different example problems and
then the goal for you is just kind of
think through for that particular
problem what would be kind of sensible
intermediate steps for um for the agent
and how would you actually represent
those different intermediate steps. So
um the first task is a robot that wants
to learn how to cook Italian dishes like
fkatcha. Uh what would kind of the
intermediate steps for those cooking
tasks look like if it needs to kind of
control its motors to complete that task
and the representation for that. Um the
second one is maybe you're uh developing
an autonomous driving bike uh and you
want it to break down kind of navigation
and biking to various locations on
campus. The third is a language model
that is drafting legal briefs, uh, which
is also a rather complex and involved
process. And then the last is maybe a
web agent that needs to plan and book
oneweek vacations for users. Um, so I'll
give you a couple minutes to pick one of
these, discuss with your neighbor what
intermediate goals would look like, uh,
and then we'll come back and and
discuss.
>> Uh, does anyone want to share what they
discussed? Cool. Yeah. So, um for number
two, one way that you could address it
is the different intermediate goals
could be kind of uh like way points um
towards that particular goal location uh
that you want to reach and then the
representation for that could be GPS
coordinates and the reward for the
low-level policy would be like how close
are you to those GPS coordinates. Um so
yeah, something like that makes sense.
Anyone else want to share
either for that problem or a different
problem? Yeah, cool. So for the fourth
one, you could there's a few different
ways you could think about it. You could
think about it as like intermediate
goals are like booking day one, booking
day two, booking day three, or you could
have a more course defined approach
where you're like booking travel, uh
booking um uh I don't know, hotels or
whatever. Um and then specific
activities. Uh one other part of this
that I would imagine you need to do is
like kind of just generally figuring out
what does the user want uh from their
vacation. And so doing kind of high
level research first. Um, and that could
be kind of also an intermediate goal as
part of completing the task.
Did anyone pick one or three?
>> Okay, so the intermediate goals are
things like opening the cabinet, being
the eggs, and then sorry, the
representation for those goals.
>> Okay, didn't quite get to that. So, but
one thing, so a few things that you
could do for the representation for that
is it could just be a natural language.
So it could be like literally like the
string beat the eggs or open the
cabinet. Uh if for example um if you're
cooking something where you want to look
in a particular way, you could even have
an image as an intermediate goal
representation as well saying like I
want the bread to look like this. Um or
yeah that sort of thing. So you could
imagine like multimodal goal
representations as well.
So um one of the things that I kind of
wanted to convey with this exercise is
that uh often times the goal
representation that you might pick is
likely depends on the particular domain
or the particular problem. For example
like for biking it might be something
like GPS coordinates whereas for cooking
it might be language. Um for booking a
vacation it might also be in language.
Uh uh there might also be images
involved and so forth.
And um in terms of what these goal
representations might look like, um
often times you'll want it to be uh if
you're kind of developing something for
many different subtasks, you want it to
be fairly expressive. Like if you're
trying to cook lots of different um lots
of different meals, you like natural
language is something that's like quite
expressive and can describe a number of
different low-level behaviors. [snorts]
Uh ideally, it also has some structure.
Uh and so for example, if your different
goals are just like do task subtask one,
do subtask two, it's going to be kind of
hard for your low-level policy to figure
out how those relate to one another.
Whereas if you have something like GPS
coordinates, then um two GPS coordinates
that are very close to each other are
going to have similar actions and that
sort of structure will u make the
learning problem a lot easier for the
low-level policy.
Um and then the third thing is is also
picking an appropriate level of
abstraction. So
um for the kind of the the biking task
for example um you can have like a level
of abstraction that's like potentially
too um too low level. So you could have
something that's like uh kind of pedal
uh I don't know like im like current
like exact velocity for the next second.
Um you could also have something too
high level which is like uh go to the
quad or something which might not be
particularly helpful in terms of
breaking the problem down into smaller
steps. Uh and choosing the right level
of abstraction is often somewhat tricky
uh and uh can also be domain dependent
depending on the particular uh kind of
details of the problem and and the um
the application area. Uh so the question
is should we also abstract the state
space for each layer? Um this depends on
like whether or not you have access to
that like that sort of like abstraction
layer. Uh the
[snorts]
let's see often times uh even for the
high level policy it's helpful for it to
have all of the information about the
current state uh in order to make kind
of even high level goal predictions. Uh
but
yeah, there are kind of some things that
you can do. For example, you could for
example like ask a language model to
summarize uh kind of the highle
information about a state and have a
highle policy use that information. Um
but generally in practice uh you'll
often use like the same low-level like
the full state information. You don't
lose too much from doing that as well.
Um now let's talk a little bit about the
supervision for each level. And for this
I think it's helpful to kind of go
through um to kind of consider an
example. So let's um let's consider an
example where uh you're making pasta. Uh
and I chose this to be uh slightly
simpler long horizon task. And you could
imagine there being a few steps involved
for doing this. uh and we can kind of
abstractly think about uh the state
space for this task and and reaching
different intermediate steps for this.
Uh so for example um maybe let's see
let's say that this is your kind of
initial state distribution and the steps
for making pasta is that you'll need to
like get out a pot um and and pasta so
some ingredients you'll need to boil the
water and you'll also need to pour the
um pour the pasta into the boiling
water. Maybe there's also a straining
step but we maybe we can skip that for
now. And uh we could think about the um
like imagine kind of the set of states
that where you have like for example uh
you have taken out a pot. So like find a
pot uh before actually like putting any
water into it. You could have um some
states where you've now have kind of
boiled the water.
Uh another set of states where you have
uh like found the pasta
and then some other states where uh like
the pasta is cooked.
And
let's say that our if we have kind of
our low-level policy, it's going to be
trying to figure out um like how do I
take actions to reach these kinds of
states and then the high level policy is
trying to predict which like if I'm in a
given state, what command should I use
to tell the low-level policy what to do?
And generally, as we've talked about a
bit before, uh, for the low-level
policy, um, it's going to be getting
rewards that are based off of the the
low-level tasks,
um, and the kind of the goal of
something like this would be something
where, um, you're kind of moving towards
finding a pot. Maybe you're, um, maybe
then you kind of try to boil the water,
then you try to find the pasta, and then
you try to cook the pasta.
Now one thing that we talked about a
little bit before is so this is actually
deviating from this example a little bit
we'll come back to it um is we could
also just train the high level policy
and the low-level policy end to end
without any intermediate goal
representation. Uh and so we would just
for example we'd have some sort of kind
of latent goal representation that's
just the activations of the neural
network and we could kind of train all
of these just for the highle task and
and the rewards of completing the task.
Now, one important thing that is is good
to know about kind of this sort of
supervision is that if you do that, um
that's basically just a flat policy with
a different like a particular
architecture um that has some sort of
like kind of activations when you feed
in the observation twice. You can kind
of just think about that as basically a
single neural network architecture. Uh
that's basically the same as a flat
policy.
Uh and the reason why it's important to
recognize this is that um when designing
these kinds of systems, it's important
to think about where the benefits are
coming from. Whether it's coming from
additional supervision, whether it's
coming from ex structured exploration.
Uh and if you don't think carefully
about this, you could end up in a
situation where kind of intuitively if
you haven't thought about it, it's like
uh like ideally my high level policy
will do this, my low level policy will
do this without actually seeing benefits
compared to just kind of naively
training things um with a single policy.
This actually also if um for those of
you that are doing research is also just
generally uh something that's good to do
in any kind of research uh because you
never really know if the systems that
you're developing or the methods that
you're developing are going to improve
over some existing kind of
state-of-the-art method. Uh and if
you're very honest with yourself about
what might go wrong um and why you might
not actually see benefits from your new
idea uh then you can think more
critically about what sorts of things
will actually improve uh the final
results.
Cool. Um, so supervising each level. So,
um, we have the low-level policy and the
low-level policy will be trained to
accomplish the goal, not the original
task. Um, and so when you're passing in
the string of like find pot, it's going
to be getting a reward that is u trying
to kind of maximize reward for getting
to the states where you found the pot.
And the highle policy um its goal is to
predict these subtasks so that you end
up in the final state of the pasta being
cooked.
Um so this is kind of trying to
accomplish the original goal.
Now there's a couple things that can be
a little bit tricky about this. So say
that you're training these separately
and say that you've kind of trained um
you could for example think about
training a policy to find the pot and
maybe you've like gotten to a good
policy that's like really good at kind
of finding the pot and getting to the
state really reliably.
And then say for example when you have
um [snorts] and then maybe for example
when you uh train the policy for finding
the pasta
if you did this um if you weren't
exactly careful with how you did this
maybe you would think about okay maybe I
could actually just start from this
state and also try to find the pasta
from this state over here
and that's not taking into account that
actually when it's finding the pasta for
according to like the high level policy
if The high level policy actually wanted
it to find the pasta after boiling the
water where when you're when you're at
the stove. Then we actually try to
string together this low-level policy
with the low-level policy for these two.
Uh it'll actually then struggle to
transition from going to the stove over
to finding where the pasta is. Uh and
this is kind of this is basically like a
mismatch. When you're kind of training
these modular systems, you need a um and
you're training them completely
independently. You might not actually
get a system that works effectively if
the if they're not actually at some
point connected together and trained
such that this skill is starting from
states that the um where the high level
policy will actually start commanding
that task. And so essentially when
you're training uh the low-level policy
you so you have your low-level policy
actions given states and goals. you want
this policy to work for the set of
states where the highle policy is going
to command this particular goal.
Another way to think about this is that
um [snorts] and and I guess the other
thing here is also you wanted to be able
to pick the goals that actually the high
level policy would predict. So um for
the different for different
distributions of goals and different
distributions of states ideally that
low-level policy would work for whatever
states and goals the highle policy will
output.
[snorts] Um now if we haven't actually
learned a high level policy yet this
leads to a bit of a kind of puts things
in a bit of a tricky situation. Um and
likewise for the high level policy
[snorts]
if we assume that our low-level policy
is is really great um then we might not
realize that uh that it actually has
some deficiencies and that we need to
for example continue to command
something in certain states until you've
actually reached a state that a
different skill can operate in. Yeah.
Yeah. So if the low-level policy works
from particular sequences of states,
then the high level policy could learn
that it should kind of walk the
low-level policy through those states.
So you don't necessarily need your
low-level policy to work from every
state. It just needs to work for the
state goal combinations that the highle
policy is going to command. Now you
might have a situation where say that
your low-level policy um kind of knows
how to do kind of something like this.
So it knows how to go from here to here.
it knows how to go from here to here and
maybe knows how to go from here to here.
Um like with some boiled water, then you
might have some sort of gap where to
actually find the pasta you need to kind
of go back to these states. And if you
don't have a like a command um or some
way to get from here to here, then
you're going to basically have a gap in
the states that you're visited and the
high level policy will struggle um to
actually get to this state here. And so
basically one way to think about it is
you need to make sure that there's like
at least some overlap in the states from
one skill to the next. Uh and ideally
that overlap is a bit has some buffer.
Uh because if it it if for example when
you're trying to find the pasta, it only
works like if you're like standing
exactly in front of the boiled water and
not if you're like a little bit to the
right, then if your policy ends up
deciding to boil the water standing a
little bit to the right of it, then
you'll get a brittle um a brittle final
result where it will kind of struggle in
that case.
So the way to think about that is that
um I guess one way to think about it is
that if this low-level policy only works
from like this part of the
states where the water is being boiled
and the high level policy gets you here
um or the previous low level policy gets
you here then you're going to have a
little bit of a gap between here and
here um and that sort of gap can lead to
brittle performance on the full long
horizon task. Yeah. So the question is
does it have to be a fixed sequence and
can you like learn if one sequence is
more efficient than another and yeah so
absolutely the highle policy can
actually decide which sequence it wants
to do and that sequence might depend on
what's the most efficient it might also
depend on um where these um uh where the
low-level policy is most successful and
so um and one of the reasons why I
wanted to pick this example is actually
these two these two steps can be done in
any order and the high level policy
could decide that when you're here it
wants to command you to go here. Um, and
as long as the little policy knows how
to find the pasta from these states,
then um, that might be more efficient
overall. Um, there's also worlds where
maybe this would be more efficient
because maybe while you're boiling the
water, you're just waiting and you can
find the pasta in the meantime. Um,
uh, and so I guess there's also a
pouring water that and turning on the
stove and so forth. So there's more
steps involved, but um, yeah, the high
level policy can decide which order it
wants to take.
Okay. Um so the generally the way to
address this is that you can first train
them potentially completely separately.
Uh but it's important for at least one
policy to be adapted to the other. Um
and ideally um even both could be kind
of jointly adapted with each other to
optimize um to optimize reward um or
optimize some uh kind of complete
objective.
Cool. Um, one other side note I guess um
that I think is worth mentioning is that
the uh even for problems that are not
like traditionally LLM problems um LLM
problems are LLMs are actually often
pretty good at some of the higher level
reasoning that you might want to do. Uh
and so for example, if you know that you
want to cook pasta, uh if you ask a
language model what are the steps
involved with that, often times they can
actually give you that. Um and so this
is one way where you can actually um
kind of train the high level policy
completely separately from the low-level
policy and then potentially fine-tune
them um because the language model for
example might not know that um uh kind
of which order the policy the low-level
policy is best suited for um or other
things about the capabilities of the
low-level policy. Um and so that sort of
adaptation process even though language
walls are pretty good this that sort of
adaptation process is really important.
Um, also if you ask um if like a robot
is in front of a coffee machine and you
ask the robot to get some coffee for you
um if the language model doesn't
actually pay attention to that image, it
might say that it might tell the robot
like oh can you like go out and buy
coffee um like at Starbucks or
something? Uh and the robot might not
have that sort of affordance that sort
of ability to do that. Um and so kind of
adapting these two together that's
another example where adapting these two
high level and low level policies
together is quite important.
Okay,
the last key design choice that we
haven't talked about yet is when to move
from one task to another. So, we
outlined this process here and we didn't
really spend that much time thinking
about like how long do you repeat
sampling from your low-level policy to
accomplish a goal. Um and essentially
it's like how how often do we requer a
new goal from the high level policy to
pass to the low-level policy.
Um so basically yeah this step right
here.
So there's two
natural options for this.
The first natural option is to requery
the highle policy whenever the low-level
policy has completed the goal. So when
it has boiled the water, that's when you
tell it to go find the pasta, for
example.
Um, and the way that this would look
like is at this point, your low-level
policy not only needs to predict action,
but it also needs to predict whether or
not it successfully completed the task.
Uh, and this could be either with some
sort of binary indicator or through some
sort of progress indicator. uh you could
think about this done not done sort of
as a success classifier for the task.
Um and then the other option uh that's a
bit simpler uh but maybe less elegant in
some ways is just to simply requer the
high level policy after some fixed
number of time steps. So maybe you query
the low-level policy um like at 50 Hz
and you query the high level policy um
once every second. Uh so then you would
be quering the high level policy after
50 time steps.
So there's pros and cons of each of
these two options. Uh for the first case
where we're doing something after we've
completed a goal, uh this is actually
ideal. Like if you're to do this well,
this should be the most compute
efficient uh because you're waiting for
the low-level policy and you're not any
you don't need to kind of rethink how
you're doing the task while the
low-level policy is executing.
Um there's a couple things that are
tricky about this though. Um the first
is that it's it can actually be hard to
estimate when you're done with a a task.
Uh this is actually like it's definitely
not uh trivial to do this. Um and the
second is that you actually need to
account for mistakes that require
actually redoing some past goal. So for
example uh if you are trying to I don't
know organize some things on a table you
go grab something and then you
accidentally drop it on the ground. Uh
your sub goal should no longer be like
put that object on the table and instead
it should be to pick it up off the
ground. And this means that actually you
need to now estimate not just when
you're done but also whether or not um
you've actually like kind of
exited the states in which that subtask
makes sense.
Um then kind of going back to the fixed
number of time steps. Um this is less
ideal because we're going to be probably
wasting some compute. uh and there's
going to be a trade-off between spending
more compute thinking through what the
next goal should be um versus if this n
is too long then you're going to be
delayed and transitioning to the new
goal where your agent will be for
example um maybe it's kind of found the
the pot it's taken out the pot and it's
waiting for a new goal it might just be
if n is too long it's just going to be
sitting there with the pot because it's
like okay I found the pot um and that's
the goal that it's getting uh and
there'll be some delay before it then
moves on to actually finding the pasta
or pouring water into the pot. So,
there's this kind of trade-off between
how long N should be. Um, generally
because you don't want these like really
long delays, you'll pick N to be fairly
small or fairly frequent.
Um but with when it is smaller you're
then going to be placing more burden on
your high level policy um because it
needs to be making accurate goal
predictions uh more frequently on more
states
and you'll be spending more compute as
well.
So both these have pros and cons. Uh
in general uh the if we wanted to think
about like kind of how these pros and
cons relate to each other, we can think
about how these pros and cons lead to
different downstream performance.
And
with regard to like estimating when
you're done and accounting for mistakes,
if you actually make a mistake in
estimating when you're done, then you
could actually end up in a situation
where the agent is like perpetually
stuck. If it thinks that it's um if it
thinks that it's not done but it is
actually done then it will actually just
stay in that state because the low-level
policy will uh kind of keep on
predicting this like won't actually be
making any more f further progress on
the task. [snorts] Um so this actually
has a pretty kind of rough outcome uh
for these kinds of errors even if
they're infrequent.
Um and then for option two uh if you
make a mistake in predicting the subtask
uh because you're quering the high level
policy more frequently uh this also has
a bad outcome which is that the
low-level policy might kind of stop
making progress on the final task and
might be taking n the wrong actions for
end steps until you get hopefully a more
accurate goal prediction.
uh and generally between these two
things uh these errors are more fatal.
Uh and as a result they kind of
typically a lot of the hierarchal
systems out there opt for choosing
option two because of the simplicity and
because um some of the mistakes that the
highle policy might make when it's
queried more frequently are less fatal
than mistakes with regard to estimating
when you're done and like what subtask
um whether or not you should kind of
reaccount for past goals. It's also
worth mentioning that you could
potentially combine these where you try
to estimate progress, but then if it's
been a long period of time, then you
re-query anyway. Um, but yeah, the
takeaway is that generally option two is
typically what people do where you just
query at a fixed lower frequency.
Cool. Um, so let's look at some example
systems. Um, and uh I guess one thing
that I'll mention is that hierarchy is
like uh pretty popular these days. So,
um, here are four systems that were all,
um, kind of announced in the last like 5
months, four months. Uh, and they
actually all use hierarchal systems. So,
these are all like fairly long horizon
tasks where you're like cleaning a
bedroom, uh, putting like handing over
objects and and kind of pouring them or
putting them into bins, uh, putting away
objects into a fridge, putting fruit
into bowls.
And if you look at the architectures for
these things, they uh they all have some
sort of higher level model that's
predicting intermediate goals and some
lower level model that is kind of
predicting low-level actions. Um these
are in robotics domains. Likewise, in uh
language model domains, things like
chain of thought where you're kind of
reasoning through intermediate steps and
then actually outputting tokens for
those steps is also uh really popular
for completing more challenging uh
language tasks.
Cool. Um so I want to cover a few
examples of these systems. Uh, and I
picked examples that I think illustrate
a few different design choices that are
helpful and actually have comparisons on
those design choices that kind of
elucidate some of the benefits of one
design choice versus another. [snorts]
Um, so let's start with talking about
hierarchal imitation learning systems.
Uh, and we'll start with language sub
goals. Uh so the
um and let's first talk about like what
the data would look like for training a
hierarchal imitation learning system
with language sub goals.
So um the data this will be kind of a
real robot example and we um what the
data looks like is actually it's going
to use data of a long horizon
demonstration of completing the complete
long horizon task. Uh and so this case
the task is to make trail mix uh and put
the trail mix into a bag
and with this long horizon demonstration
for the full task uh it will then be
segmented into uh with uh language
labels for each segment. Uh and in this
case the segments in the data can have a
variable length. So variable um like you
might kind of if for example uh the kind
of the robot trajectory looks something
like this then you might have like the
first subtask is some is like something
like this the second subtask is maybe
shorter the third subtask is maybe
longer so you'll have variable frequency
in the data uh but the actual system
will later be using a fixed frequency
where it's kind of re-querying um more
frequently than like the the typical
segment length in the data.
Um, so these are different language
labels. These labels can either be
kind of recorded during data collection
where you're actually saying I'm going
to pick up the bag and then do a
demonstration of picking up the bag,
then say I'm going to pick up the metal
scoop. Do a demonstration of that uh in
sequence. Uh or you could do it post
talk where you just collect the full
demonstration and then with a labeling
interface label like this segment is
picking up the bag, this segment is
picking up the middle scoop, this
segment is getting M&M's and so forth.
Um so we have segmented demonstrations
with the associated language command. Um
here's another example of what this
would look like where uh and this kind
of shows that like one segment might be
longer for picking up a slice of cheese.
um a different segment might be shorter
for putting the cheese on the bread uh
and so forth.
Cool. And then once we have this data,
we'll train a high level policy and a
low-level policy with imitation
learning. And the highle policy will be
outputting the language labels from the
observations and the low-level will be
using will be taking the language labels
and the observations and predicting the
actions.
So um what this looks like is taking u
an image observation to an RGB image
passes into a high level policy that's
trained to predict the language label
and then you'll have a low-level policy
that takes the language as in addition
to the the the observations in this case
uh the the work chooses to use not just
RGB images but also joint angles uh as
input to the lowle policy and generally
you can have it's okay to have actually
this sort of mismatch between
observations for the high level and the
lowle policy and then the lowle policy
outputs uh joint commands uh and the
lowle policy operates at 50 Hz uh and I
can't remember the exact frequency of
the high level policy but I think it's
something around um like one herz one
hertz
[snorts]
cool
so that's the general setup um now we
also learned about Dagger uh and you You
can think about if we just do imitation
learning on the offline data, we might
have issues where we're training these
like somewhat independently although the
data is at least of the full long
horizon task.
And uh we can actually use Dagger uh
with these systems uh with both on both
the low-level policy and the high level
policy.
Um now one thing that's pretty cool is
that actually for the high level policy
we can actually update the highle policy
with language supervision and so dagger
on the high level policy is actually in
language space not in joint space.
Um and so uh in in this particular
approach you in principle you can do
dagger on both lowle and high level. In
this particular approach, if you're to
do it on the high level with freezing
the low level, you would um kind of be
running the policy uh the full system
and then you would then kind of type or
speak a language command that is going
to override the highle policy.
Um and then then kind of continue
collecting data and then at some point
you might give control back to the high
level policy
and then from there you can fine-tune
and actually do gradient steps on data
that has these kinds of language
interventions um to actually fine-tune
the high level policy. And when you do
this together with the high level policy
and the low-level policy acting um as
one system then you could actually adapt
the high level policy to deficiencies in
the low-level policy. Um so for example
if there's one language command that the
low-level policy makes a mistake on then
you could actually issue some
corrections to help uh compensate for
that mistake.
Um so as a so yeah I guess to summarize
we'll we can train the high level policy
and the low level policy both with
imitation and then freeze the low-level
policy and update the highle policy with
Dagger by supervising on language
corrections.
Um and so as a video of what this looks
like um these yellow
um commands are showing the output of
the highle policy and then the robot
motions are showing the output of the
low-le policy.
Uh and the
so at the beginning the um the high
level policy is saying pick up spoon.
The robot picks up the spoon. Uh move
the spoon towards me. So then it says I
want some peanuts. So then the lowle
policy scoops peanuts. Then the high
level policy says move the scoop into
the bag. The lowle policy starts to do
that. Um at this point you'll actually
notice that the robot's about to make a
mistake. And so that's when you can
intervene. And um instead of telling the
robot move the scoop in the bag because
it seems like the low-level policy isn't
going to do that correctly, you could
then intervene and say um
you can intervene and say move the scoop
into the bag or sorry instead of saying
move the scoop inside, you say move the
left arm to the left, go higher
um move the scoop into the bag then. And
so these user commands are overriding
the high level policy. And then at this
point you can give um control back to
the high level policy and the high level
policy predicts pour into the bag. Um
and uh
and get some banana chips and so forth.
Um so that's kind of what this sort of
dagger intervention looks like in the
high level space. And then after you
fine-tune the high level policy on those
kinds of interventions, the the high
level policy can then self-correct and
know that the lowle policy is making a
mistake where it was about to make kind
of the same sort of mistake again. And
then the high level policy says go
higher and then move the scoop into the
bag to kind of uh prevent that sort of
mistake. And so this is an example of
like the high level and lowle policy
adapting together um uh to account for
uh deficiencies.
Cool. Um now we've talked about
hierarchy versus flat policies. Uh you
could ask like you can actually do a
comparison like in this particular setup
does hierarchy compare like um
outperform using a single flat policy to
do the long horizon task. Uh this
comparison is actually from a different
research paper but um it has basically
the same approach and it finds that for
in terms of like task progress there's a
34% improvement from using hierarchy
versus training a single policy to do
the the full long horizon imitation
learning task. Um and in terms of like
following instructions there's also um a
gap. This is kind of this instruction
accuracy metric.
Um and you can also actually compare
Dagger to imitation learning. uh in the
high level for the high level policy and
you can also see that there's like an
improvement from using Dagger compared
to just using vanilla imitation learning
and this is the sort of improvement that
you get from adapting the policies
together.
Cool. Um and then generally with
hierarchy you can the kind of the nice
thing about hierarchies you can do
longer horizon tasks. And so um with
this full system you can for example um
get the robot to put three objects into
a ziploc bag which is like traditionally
a pretty difficult task to do uh
especially in one go.
Um and and likewise with a similar
system, you can also uh get a robot to
uh the kind of the high level command is
clean the bedroom and then the low-level
policy will output things like uh pick
up shirt, put shirt in basket, pick up
shirt, put shirt and basket um and later
uh pick up the pillow, um adjust the
blanket, put the pillow at the top of
the bed, adjust the pillow, pick up
tissue, put the tissue in the trash can,
uh and so forth. And so these are things
that are like would be very hard to do
if you just trained like a single flat
policy.
So instead of using language, we could
also use images as an intermediate
representation.
Um and so what this would look like is
instead of having the highle policy
output language, you would output a goal
image. Uh and so it' be like this is the
kind of an image of what I want you to
accomplish in the future. Um, in
practice, you can use a generative model
like an image editing model to do this
that takes as input the image of the
current step and then edits that to look
like an image at a future time step that
you want the robot to achieve.
Uh, and then the low-level policy would
no longer be language conditioned, but
would rather be a goal image condition
policy. Um, and so you can think of this
as a kind of like an inverse like a
multi-step inverse model that takes as
input and the current image, some future
image, and then outputs the actions that
you can take to get to that goal image.
Um, and then both of these will be
trained again with imitation learning.
And one of the things that's pretty nice
is that you don't you no longer need to
segment videos with language annotations
to do this. Uh, you just need the videos
of the long horizon task. And to train
this high level policy, you can train it
on like robot data and predict like
future images in the trajectory like
from 1 second or or 5 seconds into the
future or 10 seconds in the future. Um,
but you can also actually train this
high level policy using like YouTube
videos or something like that uh to
predict like what are future images that
might accomplish some long-term goal.
Uh, and so that sort of data, that sort
of unlabeled video data can be helpful,
especially if data from like the robot
is more sparse.
Um, so then an example of what this
looks like is
um, say the task is to move the wooden
bowl to the top of the table. You pass
that into the highle policy that then
generates images which are shown with
the pink border. And then that generated
subgoal image with the pink border is
passed as input to the low-level policy
which then predicts actions. Um and both
of these policies again are trained with
imitation learning on um on
demonstration data and potentially also
uh if the high level policy can be
trained on video data as well. So this
one is putting the toothpaste in the
wooden bowl. You can see that it
generates these sub goal images of like
for example holding the toothpaste above
the bowl. it then reaches that then it
generates a sub goal of like lowering
the arm and so the robot lowers the arm
um to complete the task.
Uh and then this last example the goal
is to open the drawer. The first sub
goal is to like put the the gripper on
the handle. Then the next sub goal is to
move the gripper to the right so that it
opens and so forth.
Another thing that's nice about this
sort of approach is that if you don't
have a like if if your policy sees
objects that it's never seen before that
are hard to describe in language, then
you um that's something that that it can
more easily describe in images because
it it know it can more easily generalize
across the objects that it's seeing and
generate pixels for those images if it
doesn't know like what the semantic name
for that object is.
Cool. Um and then for this sort of thing
you can also do a comparison on like is
it helpful to include those unlabeled
videos for training the highle policy.
Uh and if you only use robot data you
get performance that looks like this.
And if you add videos of humans for
training the high level policy um you
get like uh an increase in performance
uh compared to just using the robot data
to train the policies.
Now um
we talked earlier about how chain of
thought can replace hierarchy and
there's also approaches that have
developed chain of thoughts versions of
this where you can have um some highle
task and the current observation and
then actually like output either sub
goal images or subtasks. You can also
have other representations like bounding
boxes or wayoints um and then output the
action. uh and there are uh some like
recent approaches from the last like one
year basically like quite recent uh that
do something like that. Uh the
[clears throat]
other thing to note is that this is with
imitation learning and we we'll talk
about reinforcement learning in a
minute. Uh but generally for these large
scale systems uh to date for the most
part they use imitation learning uh more
so than reinforcement learning and
fine-tuning them with reinforcement
learning um is in some ways an open kind
of research question for like what is
the best recipe for accomplishing that
at large scales. Uh and the it's also a
pretty important research direction
because if we think about this slide
right here um the kind of performance of
these systems is still not like super
super reliable. Um and these are these
are I should mention these are in pretty
challenging situations with like held
out objects um that the robot hasn't
seen before. So that it's kind of out of
distribution compared to what it saw
during training. Um but if we had a way
to to train these with reinforcement
learning then we should be able to get
these performances uh to be much higher
compared to using imitation learning. So
the question is um like we talked about
personalized recommendation systems and
um it could hierarchy be useful for
that. Uh generally
h I can't like it's not something that
I've seen before and generally when I've
seen um hierarchy it's usually been for
like pretty like longer horizon problems
and tasks that are more complicated. um
in like language modeling it's been used
for um
for like math problems essentially and
like kind of things where you need to uh
kind of have multiple steps for
completing something. Um yeah I could I
could think about it. Yeah. So in this
case the highle policy is an image
generative model and what it does is
it's going to take as input it's trained
to take as input um like an image
observation and some sort of highle goal
so like goal high level and then
uh you have a neural network and that
neural network is going to be trained to
output O t + Okay. Um, so it's going to
be trained to generate an image of a
future image. Um, yeah, train to
generate a future image. Uh, and you can
get this is if you have videos, then you
don't need language annotations to get
this image. Uh, in terms of the
architecture, um, it's using a diffusion
model to generate these images. That's
why you saw the noise kind of um, moving
into the image. Uh, yeah. In the
direction of the goal. Yeah. So this
particular goal might be on the horizon
of like um I don't know like a minute
and this sub goal could be uh in the
direction like it could just be like I
don't know 10 seconds in the future
something like that. Yeah. So in terms
of using image editing models uh that
sort of general pre-training can be
useful because it teaches the model how
to generate images in general. And then
the videos that are used um they're
actually videos of people doing
different tasks that have a like a
single language annotation for what the
person is doing in the whole video. Um
and so those videos um are like
especially useful to include because
they're kind of pretty relevant. If
instead you included um like random
videos on YouTube, uh it's a little bit
harder. Um but it might still teach it
about like uh if there's some like
future thing, what are kind of what are
images that could happen in the future?
And that is useful pre-training for this
kind of task. Yeah. So you're asking
like what if the language isn't accurate
and what if the this is like a sketch
instead of uh like a real image. Um so
good question. Uh the I guess first if
you wanted to use sketches here uh you
would just want to ideally like train a
low-level policy to be able to use that
sort of thing. And there are actually
approaches that have like taken images
and you can kind of convert them into a
sketch and train a low-level policy to
do that. Uh and so and you don't
actually necessarily need this to be a
full image. There's and these are just
kind of I should mention two example
representations. Um and language is
actually particularly popular as an
intermediate representation. Uh but
there's lots of other representations
you could use uh including sketches,
including like um I don't know like a
trace of where you want the robot to go
or something like that. Uh and then in
cases where the language isn't accurate,
uh if it is describing something that's
like different, then often times the
robot will then follow that different
task um until it's been told to do
something different. Uh and so that if
the high level policy is predicting
language that is bad, then the the
system will suffer. Uh there are some
cases where the low-level policy might
also ignore the highle policy uh and and
still um like if it if it you kind of
give it gibberish, it might just kind of
um have some sort of in some ways like
kind of default behavior because it was
trained to output actions and um it
often like will like for like different
states. Um, for example, if it is in if
it's like holding the pasta right here,
uh, then even regardless of any sort of
language input, chances are the next
action is actually to pour it. And so if
you don't give it a language instruction
or if you give it a noisy language
instruction, it might still continue to
pour it just because it it knows that
for that state, typically that's what
you do next. Um, now let's talk briefly
about hierarchal reinforcement learning.
So when I was bringing up examples of
this, I think that the hierarchal
imitation learning systems are are like
quite recent and I don't have too many
um [snorts] I think exciting examples or
examples that I was excited about with
regard to hierarchal reinforcement
learning but the there are a few example
systems that you can look at and I think
that generally getting these kinds of
systems to work really well like
potentially on top of the initialized
hierarchal imitation learning systems is
something that would be that's I think
really exciting and important to
explore. But generally in terms of like
what has been done and what exists, uh
you can do hierarchal reinforcement
learning with trying to reach different
states. Um and this could be the
relative target position of some agents
or some objects.
And um kind of one cool work that that
does this is it has this like
four-legged ant agent uh that you might
have worked with in uh in homework one.
and its goal is to get over here. Uh,
and to get over there, it actually needs
to push this object to the right and
then move there as a result. Uh, and
then there's also this example where it
needs to get over here. If it tries to
go directly there, it will fall in this
creass. And instead, it needs to push um
and make a little bridge for itself and
then walk over and walk over here. Um,
and this is these are pretty long
horizon problems where if you just try
to take actions greedily, you won't be
able to get to the goal.
Uh and so the work trained a goal
condition policy uh conditioned on goal
states uh with a reward of reaching
those goal states and then it trained a
high level policy to output goal states
um and those kind of goal states are the
highle actions.
Um but actually also used hindsight
reabeling for the highle policy uh to um
kind of actually reabel highle actions
or to relabel the goals that the high
level policy should output in certain
circumstances. Um and it used an off
policy algorithm to train uh to train
this in order to allow it to work
effectively.
Um
and then another work that does
hierarchal reinforcement learning uh
uses language goals. So you can do goal
states, you could also do language
goals. Um this trains a language
condition policy. It uses um language
relabeling. Uh so instead of goal
reabeling, it does hindsight reabeling
in language space. Uh and then the high
level policy is trained to output
language. Uh which is actually a pretty
difficult task. Um, and it uh, again,
this this is a work that's not too
recent. And so it's from like 2019. Um,
and so the tasks are relatively simple.
Uh, where it's trying to be able to
arrange these different objects in
particular order where you need to like
push the green object, push the red
object, the blue object, and so forth.
Cool. Um and then the last thing that
I'll mention is that uh we've talked
about these scenarios where you're
supervising the low-level policy to like
reach some goals and the high level
policy to output those goals. Now, um
there's in some ways like a really cool
research direction of instead of
actually supervising it to do certain
goals, can you actually discover
intermed like discover subtasks or
discover skills that might be useful
without requiring supervision on those
low-level skills. Uh, and here's one
example of a work that studies that
where it, um, in this kind of simple
half cheetah agent that you might have
also seen in one of your homeworks, uh,
it's able to learn skills like backing
up, walking forward, uh, doing, uh, I
think a a front flip, uh, and so forth.
And then in principle, if you discovered
skills without supervision, then you
could try to sequence those together to
do harder tasks. Um but this is
generally still an active research area
and something that's pretty challenging
uh to scale up especially in very large
state spaces.
Um cool. Uh that's it and next time
we'll be talking about reinforcement
learning for robotics specifically
learning with autonomy and um a guest
lecture from Ashish Kumar on the Tesla
Optimus team.